yo yo what up scope peace
I'm here with Harold I'm comin yeah and
we're having a discussion that we
thought it might be worth it to share
with you
yeah we need a we need a UH I don't know
I mean there's no a good way to like
should like put this somewhere
put it on something any conversation did
I see the hallway so oh the poor shit
aw little Boyd's a dog now the real
question is what does it do for cat does
it run cat well if this is gonna be kind
of different company bashing well okay
is the front camera cuz we have to see
the CoV Gail put it against code names
here we got code names gonna be on our
phone mount for now okay get in the
frame turn it sideways we're excited to
hear about power companies yeah yeah so
yeah welcome to uh his periscope good
thing I'm on my high quality iPhone X
here where you can see great things on
camera top yeah so what you're talking
about is is you know I've been hacking
cell phones for a long time it's kind of
what I do how I used to be and I was
just having the Toyota ECU's and I was
talking about how Toyota you see you
look a lot like 1990s cell phones I
don't I don't even mean this is an
insult right I don't even mean this is
like oh yeah we're ripping on Toyota but
when you think about what was added like
there's not only no security and these
ECU's there's no integrity checks really
there's no like strong integrity checks
they don't do like a Shah of the data
and compare it to a hash right so if you
think of it like you can't have security
without integrity integrity is checking
for accidental bit flips security is
checking for malicious bit flips but
yeah so they don't there's no there's no
security but oh these issues all filled
by the companies that ship the cars no
sword
these Toyota use user felt like again so
practically den so I don't own by Toyota
like react built Honda but they're not
really owned by Toyota because genso
also built easy use for Subarus
yeah that's an awesome build CPU search
they'll decease ubers yeah so I mean you
know to be honest I always talk about
how the car companies are really just
marketing agencies and integrators yeah
they yeah so this is a Paul Graham tweet
that we just talked about and it said
when the iPhone came out every phone
manufacturer understood that they needed
to copy the iPhone when the Model S came
out the car manufacturers still don't
understand that they need to copy the
Model S I mean maybe they understand but
they're just not don't have the dynamic
company to to make these changes right
if they buy all these easy-to-use from
other companies you have this five year
cycle like they're just not theirs can't
but it's not even like and you know
what's next in the five year cycle right
their development roadmaps are not very
secret it's not like they're planning to
put big powerful Linux computers in cars
any time soon I just don't see it but
maybe maybe they have this fear of like
computers in general because of their
five-year like updates right maybe they
don't want to put like didn't use them
Danis thin because they're like in five
years gonna be old anyway and then as a
result they put even older shit yeah
yeah I mean yeah I guess what they would
have to do is really separate out the
hardware and the car base from the
software yeah yeah yeah make sense to
them I think it's all kind of it's all
kind of you the same but like it's not
even 2000 era cellphones I used to hack
2007 is like Motorola RAZR kind of stuff
I mean they're not the security's
nowhere near on the level of like the
iPhone security but it's way better than
these ECU's which look literally like
like they look like Nokia you know Nokia
shit phones I mean for example you can
just go by how much flash they have
right so so then the old Toyota ECU's
had 512 K of flash and the new Toyota
issues have 1.5 mix this Wow and what's
even more horrifying is that it uses all
this code like the code is is spaghetti
code written in C I mean at first when I
saw this code at first when I was
reversing the first ECU the accurate ups
I thought it had to be generated I
thought that it had to be like okay this
is written and like
MATLAB and then there's some plugin
which but it's not like the more you
look at it you realize that this is
handwritten C that's being compiled yeah
but maybe that's exactly weather so they
have so much trouble going away from me
because they can either start again yeah
cuz that's unavailable right it's not
even that it's unobtainable so the
problem of field updates cars are
actually updatable they just don't ship
like they're afraid to do field updates
and they should be Toyota's calibration
update wizard if you unplug your thing
halfway through it'll break your ECU
like there's no the Honda one is a
little bit better
well the Honda checksum is actually not
the Toyota the Toyota has a verify step
which is a little bit better than a
check so you actually send all the data
twice right you send it once for a flash
and then once for verifying no this is
not particularly good
it just reverts it's not the same no no
it doesn't pervert it just says verify
failed and like you know you can try
flashing again they're kind of fucked
right no but this isn't even good right
because big flips are likely to be
correlated when you send bits down the
wire once right when you send them down
the same wire if some bits flipped
there's a nonzero chance that the exact
same bits gonna flip again yeah right
it's much better to do an integrity
check even something like a crc32 is
better than this you know if you think
that what are we uncorrelated on it's 4
billion to 1 right and that's that's
simple so the same corruption happening
is probably higher than lower or like
the one yeah or you can just use a sha
all right like it takes it took an
incredible effort of like thousands of
GPUs and some of Google's best
researchers to find a shot collision
you're never gonna you're never gonna
stumble upon a cut shot collision yeah
but it's just this is the way that like
Security's thought about and discussed
that's just absurd
right like how can they improve how can
they improve I mean none of us armed
let's start with that they could take it
out signature checking but please don't
have a signature check
please add an integrity check how could
they improve this they could write a
function in the flasher that will
compute a shot edge of the flash right
and then you know you can do this
without leaking any information you know
you put in shot hash should be this yeah
it computes the shot hash of the flash
but do they do many of these updates in
general or do they just usually just
keep using the same well they don't and
like that you know anyone who like
understands what modern kind of
practices are for any kind of code
development is you know you don't want
to have rarely-used paths in your code
you don't want to have this updater path
that okay will use it like once a year
right yeah
it's just you know why not update much
more frequently even if you're updating
nothing right it's like making sure all
your keys are rotated doing stuff maybe
that's a pro maybe they're in this like
suboptimal there's local optima we're
updating is just become so hard yeah but
they're kind of like I don't know I mean
I think they have like completely
irrational concerns around those red
ants whereas you know the big flip you
literally right now if you want to if
you want to people talk about it in
Toyota forms I've been reading the forms
lately like BMW mercedes-benz they might
be better I know a lot less about their
updating architectures I know they have
flex write which is you know further
advanced than can but the problem isn't
can yeah the problem is you know Tesla's
on can a lot too and I think Tesla has
mostly saw this updating problem you
know I bet Tesla's written like quasi
reliable updaters for all these things
that are written that are written with a
modern software stack by the way
download the calibration up there update
wizard or the J 2 v 3 for a flashing
tool for the Honda they've written in
like shit tier windows they're written
in like like like visual C++ dotnet 2003
make sure you import STD
effects done each at the top of every
file kind of shit car companies have
always worked to do this as little as
possible so how long have you I don't
know why why what why do you not why do
they not want their product to be
available you're still trying to use
learn to use Cabana work more uh wasn't
lack of integrity checks the reason the
pedal sticking thing that Toyota got
sued for honestly I don't think it was
actually a buck my understanding about
the pedal sticking thing was literally
like on two cars the mechanical pedal
got stuck down and then you know I mean
that's okay yeah someone like spills a
can of coke down there elegance right
well I mean this week yeah yeah there's
the whole thing of you give people an
excuse to complain some guy got like
pulled over for speeding he was going
like 95 on the highway he's like Oh
unintended acceleration yeah yeah that's
what it was
um do I think BMW Mercedes Toyota will
die no I don't think I want you guys
getting anyway yeah so no I don't think
any of those three companies are gonna
die I think that they have roles in the
in the future think about Toyota is they
do build a really nice cheap safe car
Toyota should not be stupid and should
you know it let somebody else build
their build it I mean you and you see
the thing is you wouldn't actually give
me enough authority right you'd make me
like a level 3 manager so you see the
cab of my toe a minute right they make
me like a level 3 manager and I would
spend my whole time convincing people
that like this yeah I'm not doing that
what car companies are good Tesla to be
honest it that's it yeah but that's part
of the problem I mean that that's means
I don't know if there's just no other
companies that are doing this properly
so these companies car companies don't
get
because nobody's gonna yeah yeah I mean
I still don't think they're all gonna
die right they're not all gonna die
Tesla yeah um Tesla has production
difficulties and Tesla also is never
gonna make gasoline-powered cars yeah
and they also don't make $80,000 cars
right there I will see Tesla going back
right sometime maybe
Tesla wants the Motul right yeah the
model 2 was like a yeah yeah I don't
think I don't think the cost
I don't think Tesla is a luxury brand
and its kind of not right like III wrote
it a Model S at a 2008 Mercedes s-class
um was my car and everyone a model
lasted I'm like this is all right but
it's not it's not a luxury car yeah it's
it's like the acceleration is really
cool it's a little more close to a
sports car and it's very safe I do like
that but that's not you know you look at
the interior and it's like it's like
plasticy and offensive good it's nothing
yeah it's a DJ um so if Toyota wants to
integrate your tech into their car
absolutely it's all the source I would
love to see Toyota integrate it the
monopolistic structure of car companies
means they don't have to improve they're
not monopoly right I don't
yeah interior model s not loggia so I'm
talking about um all IBM's I'll sign
licensing deals with Microsoft yeah and
where I BM and Microsoft today Microsoft
is desperately trying to pivot to be a
cloud company and selling you office SAS
I mean Microsoft's business model used
to be Bill Gates the reason he's a
billionaire he invented software license
yeah that's what Bill Gates invention
he's like well what if instead of
selling you the license to das he
$10,000 we show you $50 per computer oh
that's a lot of $50 right like I just
imagined Bill Gates like going like this
and Steve Ballmer and him were like
dancing around Steve Ballmer throws a
chair across the room right yeah yeah
yeah Tesla Tesla seems to be trying very
hard to do all these things right but
there's still me
very expensive cars that are less
luxurious than their gasoline
competitors yeah um so if you think
about the model three right you think
about what the model crew is gonna be
priced out like right now its
competitive with an Audi a4 yeah that's
probably right yeah but it's not
profitable I wouldn't worry about yeah I
mean okay I think it's all reasonable
but just hasn't been done yet right so
yeah and we need a bit more time to be
sure that you say that yeah the
strategy's definitely better I mean
you're telling me about like the Tesla
battery factory thing right yeah it's
something that just so obviously makes
sense yeah our our Panasonic and the
competitor is like even really trying
Tesla will not make it one big recall
and they are finished yeah well why do
you think that like okay there's a
there's a recall for something right so
first off first off
90% of recalls for other cars are bring
your car to the dealership so we can
plug in a wire and one calibration
update wizard on our shitty Windows
laptops ease it out like like what's the
recall okay there's some like bog and
Tesla's ABS okay we understand we're
fixing it we're getting it out we're
gonna you know most recalls people don't
bring the car back so Tesla gets a much
higher penetration rate and Tesla does
it in a few weeks
what do you mean one big wrinkle what's
the what's it gonna be recall for um you
know maybe you can have something like
like the airbags but okay what does that
what does that cost them right they've
maybe the cars back they fix the airbags
they sue the airbag company not that big
of a deal um how hard was it for Tesla
that yeah the car manufacturers
definitely want status quo most recalls
are probably a suppliers fault yeah um
because the thing is everything I'm a
Tesla that wouldn't be the suppliers
fault is uh sustainable yeah car
accidents kill over 1 million people per
year yeah that's true how many people
are those people in Tesla's yeah I mean
they're very stable cars they're just
kind of
surely good in there you know I think
the active safety features are gonna
play a huge role in mitigating car
accidents the future every most car
accidents just cause to the stupidest
reasons yeah a lot of people die I mean
you know that's uh I think now I when I
was a little bit younger suicide was my
most likely cause of death no big cars
when you're a teen you're more likely to
crash a car and commence 16 um Microsoft
tried to emulate car companies in the
90s they were financially successful for
a while here's the thing and there's
something that people always point out
to be about Microsoft Microsoft is
actually still incredibly financially
successful yeah Microsoft because
companies in the world of blame for a
minute it's not hard to see for us door
you got you think comma a I will make it
I think in a couple years you're gonna
have these companies just looking around
and be like holy shit that's what calm a
I was doing oh my god we're fucked
I mean what am I missing
right well if I'm missing something Oh
like explain to me what will never work
and explain to me or either explain to
me a what won't work or be where a
competitor will be me yeah we view our
competitors or the car companies rightly
we've always talked about this let's
call me guys business model it was very
similar to the car companies we sell
hardware but we don't sell cars and sell
software for your cars the idea um tesla
wants to get legal exception i don't
even know what that means I'm missing a
pinstripe suit and a focus on only money
on the on the short term maybe that's
not missing right no business people
answer that business people come to me
you know why don't you just why do i why
do i want your opinion well why do i why
do I need your opinion why do I want
your opinion why do I want to let you
know in the company I don't know about
sales all right I'm sales the sales is
one thing and you really are
I want some kid to do some internet
marketing for me right get some like kid
to like you know going gone like SEO
doesn't work anymore I don't know
bison Instagram followers or something
um how would I convince companies to buy
myself right I won't I'll just beat them
manufacture flying cars yeah they've
been talking about that for years how
about Chinese copycats let's see if any
of them ship how do we stall the shipper
data big hard drives in the cloud um
comma a I can win only because small
elite teams build better software that's
generally true um that generally is is
true I mean I I've always viewed
software is much more like a like an art
project this alright like just imagine
art phones I just imagined we're asking
like Oh a 16 your Sistine Chapel all
right let's get IBM to paint the Sistine
Chapel okay well we're gonna spend six
months on the design requirement phase
author code yeah when will common points
be monetized eventually TM hackers and
painters by Paul Graham disruption is
usually caused by people who don't have
much to lose by challenging the status
quo I mean like whoever has anything to
lose right what are we gonna lose what's
the worst-case scenario we don't win Oh
whole life was a waste no what am I
gonna do I'll have to go back to
flipping burgers do you have a website
yeah comma dot hey hi
testing theories having quality problems
it's hard yeah sorry um you put it this
way Tesla's quality problems will be
fixed long before Toyota's ECU flashing
changes planning to do more funding
rounds yeah and we have something Y on
Subaru because like you know
like superoes man short-term kills bro I
mean yeah it's it's uh it's a disease
it's really a disease like people don't
know capitalism is anymore i people
think of capitalism is all we're gonna
have to like you know rape and pillage
and get all the profits now I mean it's
like the mentality in the world today
how stupid only if they don't run out of
cash but what do you mean by run out of
cash right like there's no way Tesla's
like oh we're out of cash I guess we
gotta shut the business down yeah that's
gonna be their their problem
um self raising cars I'm actually gonna
be at a wedding that week I didn't
realize but I think we'll send someone
commoner wrap it's like two weeks oh
it's in two weeks yeah people think
cronyism equals capitalism yeah I look
and you know also people people hate on
capitalism capitalism is phenomenal you
just need to get rid of the cronyism um
biggest fear of someone showing up at
Cobo with a dump truck full of money on
a what do you mean if we raise another
investment round it's wrong I'm gonna
give her a board seat it's like if I
could give up majority control what are
you Oh a dump truck of money from me
what the hell would I do with money I
was really I was really talking about
this like what would I do with 50
million dollars you know if I bought a
boat I'd buy a boat like you're about
yeah Wow I made a lot of money when I
was younger and I just I realized when I
was like 21 I just kind of looked around
and I'm like okay this is how much money
I have guys put the hands here right we
gotta do this to scale and
this is how much money I've spent in my
life I don't live a very high
maintenance I mean there's a few things
you need to avoid right
don't buy boats don't buy houses don't
support dependence and don't spend tons
of money on women right like honestly if
you manage to avoid those four things
what else are people spending money on
yeah but this is pretty hard to avoid
man when the more respect you have you
spend money on it
the ones easier what the hell can that
one's easier right now the boat and the
woman's the same well you only need to
spend money good someone could someone
could someone tell me like what would I
do with money if someone gives me an
idea and I like it I'm gonna sell out
folks and hoes now car companies will
try to find my temptation
you really think Toyota let me tell you
about my temptation let me tell you what
it is I want to live in the future guys
I want to live in the future where I
don't need to buy a real boat the VR
headset that I bought for a thousand
bucks is so good i download boat
simulator 27 and oh man you should see
my boat how much you pay for it
pirated man you wouldn't download a boat
I would what do you recommend to a young
person who wants to get really good at
something just like do it and don't do
anything else
women will sleep with you if you're
exciting and fun just be exciting and
fun it doesn't matter if you have a boat
time travel I would sell out for time
travel but that's the thing right now
like none of these things I can buy with
a billion dollars if I had a billion
dollars what do I want to buy I could
buy the biggest TV TV what $500 like
this isn't money guys take a sailboat to
the Cook Islands okay so now I'm on some
remote island how's the internet in the
Cook Islands this talk about that I got
some like satellite
[Music]
[Laughter]
when I fly would I go to the moon you
know they say when there's a five-star
hotel on the moon and I can buy a ticket
for the same price is Jeff bloomin how
will come a change as a business by my
own private jet
why would I want to buy a private jet
now I need a place to park it
I gotta hire a pilot the pilots trying
to unionize I got to go outside I got to
go to the picket line and tell them
about why the unions are I can buy jets
for our subscription for like 10k like
again these things aren't money right
like I'm not saying you don't be poor
don't be poor but like if you're making
like 100k a year pretty much no matter
what you want to buy as long as you
don't have dependents and you don't
spend your money stupidly you can get it
I like this one in scales linearly so
that's not too bad either no no no no
dependents are bad dependents are bad
because the problem with dependents is
they will spend your money without a
care of how you got work oh that's true
right like like that's what the
dependents don't stare and scale
linearly because they won't have the
same frugal attitude you do I'm a are vr
porn I can disappoint it but I'm really
excited about that if I do start another
company um could we talk about vehicle
selection interface and II built that uh
all the vehicles not on there yet
they're not only we should add more
yeah but okay this dependents are bad
and dogs are not a scam those are not a
scam I mean no I always have a bigger
carbon footprint and our interesting so
interesting all those like
environmentalist cat people chole them I
mean the real thing the real thing that
is a huge environmental footprint go
guys if you want to save the environment
don't have children
yeah babies babies are really the worst
I missed that was that question twice
Capri should keep the questions on all
right any last questions we'll go we'll
go for 30 minutes so it'll go for
another another three minutes and then
uh do some work yeah we're gonna get
back to work okay we got we got shit
can't just stay around you should talk
all day you know what happened to the
man who shit talk too long the whole
world pastor by thoughts on Martin
shkreli is he really going to jail a sad
will come and hit an animal I don't know
don't hit an animal you're at the driver
babies are good for the future question
of all what's new in common this week
the pedal all again we'll get a nosh
part pedalboard today babies are good
for the future that is very questionable
I just want to live forever
why do I need to have children Pelle
forever uh will there be a point where
open policy is better than humans and
bad visibility what do you mean by sees
better right probably not on the EON you
need kind of better uh you kind of where
can you buy comma gear for crypto um
sell your crypto on G Dax are you start
hacking the brain what do you think I'm
doing man the truth about hacking the
brain is it's not sticking wires into
the brain and say I see you at pwned oh
man I haven't done that since then I
don't know yeah I don't want to be old
like Charlie Miller who's like oh I've
got to harden other Thursday SLR um I
don't know I mean I think the kids are
just better than me now I think that the
kids you DuPont Eleanor better than me
and that's like how it should be Oh a
new calibration record echo I see all
right I feel they are banned in America
right and I get some new regulations
well working with regulators gotta watch
it work with regulators what's the
question after the new localization
record yeah okay
so calibration is defined as if you know
how the car is moving and you know how
the camera is moving right so you can
think about like you have you know two
two vectors pointing out right and then
there's a two angles between the vector
there's a yaw angle and a pitch angle
right so if you have a gray panda gray
Pam does return these great things in
the satellite called Doppler shifts and
it tells you exactly what you should on
average eight dimensional yeah a lot of
satellites use that we can turn on glass
and switch to beta yeah we should do
that the Russians will read ship yeah
what do you say they put them in better
orbits yeah they did
GLONASS is much better dealing with
relativity than GPS yes but in their
defense they built at the same year as
GPS it was quite wild bad yeah that's
encom's
yeah why aren't boats fully automated
with the are there come because boat
captain unions man random question how
many hours do I work over a hundred a
week that life is work when I don't know
works the only thing I've ever really
found fulfilling in life um what else am
I gonna do ride around on my boat I
don't have a boat alright thanks for
joining Squad fan out okay what's poppin
oh no make sure you hit that subscribe
button
let's serious it up if you want quality
content like this make sure to subscribe
to our periscopes again on quick you
know we got to build a brand here we got
to build an army
um gray pan that great panel all the way
way better GPS if you make a music video
absolutely rent a boat absolutely I army
out